Guide to the Central Washington University Office of Business and Financial Affairs, Budget Files 1918-1973 (bulk 1961-1967)
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections
Central Washington University Office of Business and Financial Affairs, Budget Files
1918-1973 (bulk 1961-1967)
Central Washington University, Archives and Special Collections 400 E University Way Ellensburg, WA 98926 (509) 963-1717 http://www.lib.cwu.edu/Archives-Special-Collections archive@cwu.edu
RG068-08-09
Central Washington University, Office of Business and Financial Affairs
1.5 cubic feet 2 legal sized document cases and 1 oversized box Correspondence, memoranda, newspaper clippings, budget reports and requests in fair condition with some minor tears and foxing to older documents
This collection consists of miscellaneous files associated with Washington state legislative budget programs and funding requests created or received by the Business Office or Office of Business and Financial Affairs of Central Washington University from 1918 to 1973.
Historical Note
The Office of Business and Financial Affairs at Central Washington University was established in 1970 as a division of the Business Office. From 1933 to 1969, business and financial duties were administered by the Business Manager. Prior to 1933, the school hired an accountant to supervise the financial activities of the institution.
The files in this collection contain correspondence, memoranda and reports produced by Central Washington University in preparation for making budget requests to the state of Washington. Included in the collection are monthly budget reports (1961-1967), newspaper clippings (1945-1959), legislative budget information, student and school expenditures and various reports supporting budget requests.
Central Washington University began as the Washington State Normal School in 1891. In 1937, the school was rechristened the Central Washington College of Education. In 1961, the school became Central Washington State College and, finally, in 1977, Central Washington University.
Organized alphabetically by title of file folder. Chronological arrangement.
Open to the public for educational research.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Central Washington University. Office of Business and Financial Affairs
Ellensburg (Wash.)
Central Washington University--History; Financial records
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities; Budget--Washington (State)
College administrators--United States
- Budget for the Biennium, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 1-1)
- Budget Requests, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 1-2)
- Budget Requests – Correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 1-3)
- Budget Requests – Information, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 1-4)
- Business Management Policies and Procedures Manual, 1970 (Box-folder 1-5)
- Capital Budget Justification, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 1-6)
- Capital Improvement Program, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 1-7)
- Instructional Expenditures Per Student, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 1-8)
- Legislative Budget Committee Report, 1957 (Box-folder 1-9)
- Legislative Budget Information, 1950-1958 (Box-folder 1-10)
- Legislative Budget Requests, 1961-1967 (Box-folder 1-11)
- Meeting the Building Needs of a Growing College Population - CWSC, 1961 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Monthly Balance Sheets, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 1-13)
- Monthly Balance Reports, 1961 (Box-folder 1-14)
- Monthly Balance Reports, 1962 (Box-folder 1-15)
- Monthly Balance Reports, 1963 (Box-folder 1-16)
- Monthly Balance Reports, 1964 (Box-folder 2-1)
- Monthly Balance Reports, 1965 (Box-folder 2-2)
- Monthly Balance Reports, 1966 (Box-folder 2-3)
- Monthly Balance Reports, 1967 (Box-folder 2-4)
- Monthly Balance Reports – Correspondence, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 2-5)
- Monthly Balance Reports – Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 2-6)
- Newspaper Clippings – Budget, 1945 (Box-folder 2-7)
- Newspaper Clippings – Budget, 1947 (Box-folder 2-8)
- Newspaper Clippings – Budget, 1948 (Box-folder 2-9)
- Newspaper Clippings – Budget, 1949 (Box-folder 2-10)
- Newspaper Clippings – Budget, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 2-11)
- Newspaper Clippings – Budget, 1952 (Box-folder 2-12)
- Newspaper Clippings – Budget, 1953 (Box-folder 2-13)
- Newspaper Clippings – Budget, 1954 (Box-folder 2-14)
- Newspaper Clippings – Budget, 1955 (Box-folder 2-15)
- Newspaper Clippings – Budget, 1956 (Box-folder 2-16)
- Newspaper Clippings – Budget, 1957 (Box-folder 2-17)
- Newspaper Clippings – Budget, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 2-18)
- Request for Private Financial Assistance for the Economics and Business Administration Program, 1971 (Box-folder 2-19)
- Report to the Legislative Budget Committee, 1957 (Box-folder 2-20)
- Student Expenditures, 1918-1936 (Box-folder 2-21)
- Estimated Expenditures for Washington State Normal School, 1927-1933 (Box-folder 3-1)